

## Ruhollah Taghizadeh

POSTDOC RESEARCHER

Department of Geosciences, Tübingen University

☑ruhollah.taghizadeh-mehrjardi@mnf.uni-tuebingen.de | 希ruhollahtaghizadeh.netlify.app | ☑wj5v9 | ☑
RuhollahTaghizadeh | ✔RuhollahTaghiz

## About me\_

Evnarianca

My primary research interest is in Pedometrics with a particular focus on remote/proximal soil sensing and Digital Soil Mapping. The core of the pedometric approach integrates soil system knowledge with applied statistics, Machine Learning, geoinformatics, and Remote Sensing. I apply the most recent technology in spatial data analysis to model and predict various environmental metrics such as soils, water, vegetation, and climate.

Experience	
<b>Department of Geosciences, University of Tübingen, Germany</b> Postdoc Researcher	2017-Present
<b>Department of Plant Science, South Dakota State University, USA</b> Postdoctoral Research Assistant	2016
Faculty of Agriculture, Ardakan University, Iran Assistant Professor	2013-2017
<b>Department of Soil and Water, Agricultural Research Center, Iran</b> Geospatial Consultant	2010-2011
Education	
Faculty of Agricultural Engineering and Technology, University of Tehran, Iran PhD in Soil Science	2012
<b>Sydney Institute of Agriculture, The University of Sydney, Australia</b> Postgraduate Visiting Scholar in Digital Soil Mapping	2012
Faculty of Agricultural Engineering and Technology, University of Tehran, Iran MSc in Soil Science	2008
Faculty of Agriculture, SB University of Kerman, Iran BS in Soil Science	2005
Projects	
<b>German Research Foundation</b> Sensitivity and Response of Himalayan Timberline Ecotones to Global Warming	2022
<b>German Research Foundation</b> Transferability of Machine Learning for Soil Mapping	2020
Iranian Agricultural Research, Education & Extension Organization Digital Soil Mapping in Kurdistan	2019
Alexander von Humboldt Foundation Digital Soil Mapping with Limited Data	2017

## Research interests\_

Pedology; Digital Soil Mapping; Remote and Proximal Sensing; Spatial Data Analysis; Machine Learning; Statistical Inference; Soil Health; Climate Change; Precision Agriculture

Teaching	
Teaching As	

Teaching Assistant at University of Tübingen, Germany	2020-Present
<ul><li>Spatial Pedology and Geomorphology</li><li>Statistics</li></ul>	GS UGS
Assistant Professor at Ardakan University, Iran	2013-2020
<ul><li>Soil Genesis and Classification</li><li>Soil Erosion and Conservation</li><li>Fundamentals of Soil Science</li></ul>	UGS UGS UGS
Guest Lecture at Yazd University, Iran	2013-2017
<ul><li>Soil Mapping</li><li>Land Evaluation</li></ul>	GS GS
Fellowships, honors, awards	
Five Nominated Pedometrics Best Paper Postdoctoral Fellowship of Alexander von Humboldt Foundation Top Lecturer Award at Ardakan University Top Researcher Award at Ardakan University	2020 2017 2017 2016
Professional services	
Award Committee for the Pedometrics Commission Executive board members of ISMC Associate Editor of Frontiers in Soil Science/Pedometrics Reviewed >200 papers from >20 journals	2022-Present 2022-Present 2022-Present 2013-Present

## **Selected Publications**

- 1. Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R., Nabiollahi, K., Minasny, B., & Triantafilis, J. (2015). Comparing data mining classifiers to predict spatial distribution of USDA-family soil groups in Baneh region, Iran. *Geoderma*, 253-254, 67-77. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma. 2015.04.008
- 2. Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R., Sheikhpour, R., Zeraatpisheh, M., Amirian-Chakan, A., Toomanian, N., Kerry, R., & Scholten, T. (2022). Semi-supervised learning for the spatial extrapolation of soil information. *Geoderma*, 426, 116094. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2022.116094
- 3. Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R., Hamzehpour, N., Hassanzadeh, M., Heung, B., Ghebleh Goydaragh, M., Schmidt, K., & Scholten, T. (2021). Enhancing the accuracy of machine learning models using the super learner technique in digital soil mapping. *Geoderma*, 399, 115108. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2021.115108
- 4. Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R., Schmidt, K., Toomanian, N., Heung, B., Behrens, T., Mosavi, A., S. Band, S., Amirian-Chakan, A., Fathabadi, A., & Scholten, T. (2021). Improving the spatial prediction of soil salinity in arid regions using wavelet transformation and support vector regression models. *Geoderma*, 383, 114793. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114793
- 5. Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R., Mahdianpari, M., Mohammadimanesh, F., Behrens, T., Toomanian, N., Scholten, T., & Schmidt, K. (2020). Multi-task convolutional neural networks outperformed random forest for mapping soil particle size fractions in central Iran. *Geoderma*, 376, 114552. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114552